Russel Wright Papers
Russel Wright Papers
- Contracts
  - Commerce Department (United States) (Box 46)
  - Comprehensive Fabrics (Box 46)
  - Contract forms (Box 46)
  - Cooper, George (Box 46)
  - Cornwall Corporation (Box 46)
  - Cresca Company (Box 46)
  - CUSA - contract, 2 folders (Box 46)
  - Davis, Jacques Associates (Box 46)
  - Design and Production, Inc. (Box 46)
  - Dessauer, Walter L. (Box 46)
  - Dickie, Wm (Montreal, Canada) (Box 46)
  - Dockendorf, John (Box 46)
  - Duraware Corporation (Box 46)
  - Edson, Inc. (Box 46)
  - Englishtown Cutlery, Ltd. (Box 46)
  - Epstein, Lee (Box 46)
  - Everfast Fabrics, Inc. (Box 46)
  - Fairmount Lamp Manufacturing Company (Box 46)
  - Fazakas, Donelda (Box 46)
  - Featherweight Aluminum Products, Inc. (Box 46)
  - Finkelstein, Philip (Box 46)
  - Fischer, Irwin (Box 46)
  - Fitzpatrick, Paul (Box 46)
  - Fitzwater, Edwin (Box 46)
  - Forster Textile Mills, Inc. (Box 46)
  - Frank and Sader (Box 46)
  - Fritsche, J. Associates (Box 46)
  - Garrison Development Company (Box 46)
  - General American Transportation Company, 2 folders (Box 46)
  - General Electric Company (Box 46)
  - Giurcola, Ronaldo (Box 46)
  - Glu-Pen Company (Box 46)
  - Hambly, Frank L. (Box 46)
  - Harker Pottery Company (Box 46)
  - Hatfield Brothers, Inc. (Box 46)
  - Hedwin Company (Box 46)
  - Heintze, Walter (Box 46)
  - Hoehne, George (Box 46)
  - Honig, Herbert (Box 46)
  - Hull, John Cutlers, Inc. (Box 46)
  - Hunt Foods and Industries, Inc. (Box 46)
  - ICA Three-country (Box 46)
  - Invoices, 1959-1962 (Box 46)
  - ICA
    - Accounting matters (Box 47)
    - Billing matters (Box 47)
    - Cambodia termination (Box 47)
    - Contract analysis (Box 47)
    - Foreign operations (Box 47)
    - Overhead calculations (Box 47)
  - Imperial Glass Company (Box 47)
  - Jenkins, Albert (Box 47)
  - Kawai, Thomas M. (Box 47)
  - Keedick Lecture Bureau, Inc. (Box 47)
  - Kenyon and Eckhardt, Inc. (Box 47)
  - Knapp, Roy (Box 47)
  - Knowles, Edwin M. China Company (Box 47)
  - Krevolin, Lewis Allen (Box 47)
  - Ladge Electric Company, Inc. (Box 47)
  - Larsen, Jack (Box 47)
  - Lax, Michael S. (Box 47)
  - Leacock and Company (Box 47)
  - Leavitt, Henschel and Kawai (Box 47)
  - Leonardi, Hector (Box 47)
  - Leylon, Robert (Box 47)
  - Longbell, 2 folders (Box 47)
  - Lovell, James (Box 47)
  - Lubar and Singer (Box 47)
  - Ly, Huynh Thi (Box 47)
  - Maeda, Masami (Box 47)
  - Mahana Importing Company (Box 47)
  - Maier, Ernest M. (Box 47)
  - Mallory-Randall Company (Box 47)
  - Margittal, Tom G. (Box 47)
  - McCall's Magazine (Box 47)
  - Mutual-Sunset Lamp Company (Box 47)
  - National Silver Company (Box 47)
  - Nelson, June (June Nelson Realty) (Box 47)
  - New York World's Fair, 1939, Inc. (Box 47)
  - Northern Industrial Chemical (Box 47)
  - Oglesby, Catherine (Box 47)
  - Orbitex Inc. (Box 47)
  - Organization Russel Wright (Box 47)
  - Paden City Pottery (Box 47)
  - Paper Novelty Manufacturing Company (Box 47)
  - Patchogue-Plymouth Mills (Box 47)
  - Peerless Electric, Inc. (Box 47)
  - Petrakis, Helen (Russel Wright Serv' Elegance Company) (Box 47)
  - Pier, Edward (Box 47)
  - Poloron Products (Box 47)
  - Procter and Gamble Company (Box 47)
  - Product Counselors, Inc. (Jack Wachtel) (Box 47)
  - Putnam County Construction Company (Box 47)
  - Ramy, Alexander (Box 47)
  - Ravenware Company, Inc. (Box 47)
  - Raymond, Schenkel and Company (Box 47)
  - Raymor Manufacturing and America Designs (Box 47)
  - Raymor Manufacturing Division, Inc. (Box 47)
  - Richards Morgenthau Company (Box 47)
  - Romb, Jack (Box 47)
  - Ryan, Mary Organization (Box 47)
  - Schulhoff, Marcel and Company (Box 47)
  - Saks - 34th Street (Box 48)
  - Sanderud, Bo (Box 48)
  - Sarna (Box 48)
  - Schmertz, Herbert (Box 48)
  - Schmid International (Box 48)
  - Sears Roebuck and Company (Box 48)
  - Sharon Steel (Box 48)
  - Shenango Pottery (Box 48)
  - Shwayder Brothers (Box 48)
  - Sid Material, 2 folders (Box 48)
  - Siegel, Ellen (Box 48)
  - Silex Company (Box 48)
  - Sloane-Blabon Company (Box 48)
  - Sobotka, Walter (Box 48)
  - Sovereign Potters, Ltd. (Box 48)
  - Statton Furniture Manufacturing (Box 48)
  - Sutherland Paper Company (Box 48)
  - Sydney Chairs, Inc. (Box 48)
  - Tilbury Fabrics, Inc. (Box 48)
  - Tlietson, Inc. (Box 48)
  - Tillett, Jim (Box 48)
  - Urquhart, Thomas (Box 48)
  - US Plywood Corporation (Box 48)
  - Uyemura, Ken (Box 48)
  - VanDyck, Kenneth (Box 48)
  - Vietnamese Exhibit (Box 48)
  - Walker, Joset (Box 48)
  - Wright, Russel, Inc. (Box 48)
  - Wright, Russel Accessories, Inc. (Box 48)
  - Wright, Russel Associates, Inc. (Box 48)
- Memorabilia
  - Clippings, 2 folders (Box 49)
  - Conference notes (Box 49)
  - Display packing (Box 49)
  - Exhibitions (Box 49)
  - Fabrics (Box 49)
  - John Barrymore caricature mask (Oversize 41)
  - Logos (Box 49)
  - Mural photos, 3 folders (Box 49)
  - Mural photo enlargements (Box 49)
  - Notes - Far East trip (Box 49)
  - Office routines (Box 49)
  - Original manuscript for RW book (Box 49)
  - Photos
    - Easter party (Box 49)
    - Memorabilia (Box 49)
    - Negatives (Box 49)
    - Outdoor furniture (Box 49)
    - Ski club (Box 49)
  - Pictures - AU400 (Box 49)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Magazine clippings (Oversize 39)
    - "American Modern" clippings (Oversize 40)
    - Miscellaneous (Oversize 44)
  - Wright, Russel
    - Apartment
      - Bedroom (Box 49)
      - Cabinet - living room (Box 49)
      - Chairs (Box 49)
      - Clothes hanger (Box 49)
      - Desks (Box 49)
      - Details (Box 49)
      - Dining room table (Box 49)
      - Fireplaces (Box 49)
      - Floor and bridge lamps (Box 49)
      - Penthouse handles (Box 49)
      - Radio table (Box 49)
      - Sofa (Box 49)
      - Work cabinet (Box 49)
    - Office apartment and garden (Box 49)
    - Slides (Box 49)
    - Studio and home (Box 49)
    - Unmarked drawings (Box 49)
- Models, molds, and sample items
  Models, molds, and sample items are listed alphabetically in the inventory below, to make it simpler to locate specific types of material (e.g., bowls, dishes, etc.). Miscellaneous and unidentified items are listed at the end.
  - Bottle models (ketchup?), 8 items (Box 88)
  - Bottle models, Hunt's Catsup, 6 items (Box 66)
  - Bottles, clay, 7 items (Box 66)
  - Bowl models, small, 5 items (Box 64)
  - Bowl mold, 1 item (Box 65)
  - Bowl with filler, 1 item (Box 54)
  - Bowls, 2 items (Box 53)
  - Bowls, 3 items (Box 54)
  - Bowls (1 broken), 4 items (Box 56)
  - Bowls (1 broken), 2 items (Box 66)
  - Bowls, 3 items (Box 87)
  - Bowls/dishes, plastic, 10 items (Box 74)
  - Bowls, plastic triangular, 3 pieces) (Box 74)
  - Bowls, small, 18 items (Box 62)
  - Bowls, miscellaneous small, 13 items (Box 65)
  - Bucket, metal, 1 item (Box 50)
  - Butter dish with lid model, 1 item (Box 63)
  - Calvert Bottle models, 8 items (Box 59)
  - Calvert Bottle models, 6 items (Box 59A)
  - Ceremonial hand-drum, 1 item (Box 82)
    See also Masks, below.
  - Clock (Box 89)
  - Clock models, 2 items (Box 53)
  - Coffee pot model, written on box: "#161 A.M.C Coffee Pot working model - original plasticene model" (Box 89)
  - Cup handles, 32 items (Box 86)
  - Cup handles, 36 items (Box 87)
  - Cup handles, assorted, 10 items (Box 70)
  - Cup handles, cardboard, 28 items (Box 67)
  - Cup models, 11 items (Box 83)
  - Cup models, 2 items (Box 88)
  - Cup molds, 4 items (Box 72)
  - Cup molds, 3 items (Box 73)
  - Cup molds, 7 items (Box 83)
  - Cup molds, 5 items (Box 86)
  - Cup molds, 3 items (Box 88)
  - Cup with spout, 1 item (Box 54)
  - Cup/bowl, 22 items (Box 72)
  - Cup/bowl, 2 items (Box 87)
  - Cups, 14 items (Box 50)
  - Cups, 13 items (Box 51)
  - Cups, 3 items (Box 56)
  - Cups, 28 items (Box 73)
  - Cups with handles or spouts, 4 items (Box 65)
  - Cups, 12 items (Box 85)
  - Cups, 9 items (Box 87)
  - Cups, assorted, 21 items (Box 68)
  - Cups, assorted, 8 items (Box 70)
  - Cups, assorted, 2 items (Box 71)
  - Cups, assorted, 8 items (Box 86)
  - Cups, cardboard, 30 items (Box 67)
  - Cups, paper/plastic, 6 items (Box 74)
  - Dish, large brass, 1 item (Box 55)
  - Dish, large steel, 1 item (Box 55)
  - Dish, steel, 2 items (Box 55)
  - Dish with lid model, 1 item (Box 63)
  - Dish model sections, 3 items (Box 65)
  - Dish with mold, 1 item (Box 53)
  - Dish and plate models, paper, 38 items (Box 75)
  - Dish and plate models, paper, 49 items (Box 76)
  - Dish and plate models, paper, 56 items (Box 77)
  - Dishes, 3 items (Box 53)
  - Dishes, 9 items (Box 62)
  - Dishes, 2 items (Box 69)
  - Dishes, 8 items (Box 71)
  - Dishes, cardboard, 2 items (Box 67)
  - Dishes, halved, 2 items (Box 62)
  - Disks, colored (1 half disk), 23 items (Box 62)
  - Fixtures, wooden, 3 items (Box 55)
  - Forks, 2 items (Box 74)
  - Handmirror frames (1 broken), 15 items (Box 62)
  - Imperial aggregate trials, glass, 12 items (Box 74)
  - Knife (broken), fork and spoon models, 3 items (Box 72)
  - Ladles, 2 items (Box 56)
  - Lid models, 4 items (Box 64)
  - Lid molds, 3 items (Box 60)
  - Lids, large brass, 2 items (Box 55)
  - Lids, large steel, 2 items (Box 55)
  - Lids, plaster, 3 items (Box 57)
  - Masks, box also contains some loose parts, beads, etc.; 6 items (Box 82)
    See also Ceremonial hand-drum, above.
  - Mustard and ketchup packets, 4 items (Box 74)
  - Ornament, glass, 1 item (Box 51)
  - Pan lid model, 1 item (Box 63)
  - Pan mold, 1 item (Box 57)
  - Pan molds, 3 items (Box 60)
  - Pan molds, 4 items (Box 61)
  - Pan with lid, contains numerous miscellaneous clay models; 1 item (Box 55)
  - Paper cups, 3 items (Box 54)
  - Paper dish drawings (Box 78)
  - Paper napkin, 1 item (Box 74)
  - Pitcher, glass, 1 item (Box 81)
  - Pitcher model, 1 item (Box 65)
  - Plastic cups, 22 items (Box 54)
  - Plate, 1 item (Box 57)
  - Plate models (1 broken), 5 items (Box 63)
  - Plates, 3 items (Box 53)
  - Plates, 2 items (Box 54)
  - Plates (1 broken), 4 items (Box 56)
  - Plates (3 broken), 8 items (Box 58)
  - Plates, 8 items (Box 62)
  - Plates, halved, 9 items (Box 62)
  - Pot mold, 1 item (Box 61)
  - Pot molds, 3 items (Box 64)
  - Pots and lids, metal, 2 items (Box 67)
  - Radio (Box 89)
  - Roast turkey dinner containers, 2 items (Box 74)
  - Sample pages, 27 items (Box 77)
  - Saucer model, 1 item (Box 60)
  - Saucers, 2 items (Box 56)
  - Saucers, 6 items (Box 62)
  - Spoons, 4 items (Box 74)
  - Steubenville China set
    - Large plates, 8 items (Box 79)
    - Medium plates, 8 items (Box 79)
    - Small plates, 8 items (Box 79)
    - Large serving bowl (Box 80)
    - Small serving bowls, 4 items (Box 80)
    - Saucers (1 broken), 10 items (Box 80)
    - Sugar bowl (Box 80)
  - Steubenville China items
    Gift of Diane Zumstag, 2001.
    - Bowl, 1 item (Box 84)
    - Cups, 2 items (Box 84)
    - Large plate, 1 item (Box 84)
    - Medium plate, 1 item (Box 84)
    - Small plate, 1 item (Box 84)
    - Saucer, 1 item (Box 84)
    - Photographs, 3 items (Box 84)
  - Tags, similar to dog tags or identity tags; 4 items (Box 62)
  - Tiles, translucent greens, 12 items (Box 62)
  - Vases (1 broken), 4 items (Box 58)
  - Vases, 9 items (Box 69)
  - Vase, 1 item (Box 72)
  - Vase models, 6 items (Box 57)
  - Vase models, 9 items (Box 70)
  - Vase model, 1 item (Box 71)
  - Vase and pitcher models, 6 items (Box 81)
  - Vase models, 2 items (Box 86)
  - Models and trinkets (Box 84)
  - Models, clay, miscellaneous, 1 item (Box 56)
  - Models, clay, miscellaneous, 5 items (Box 53)
  - Models, miscellaneous, 2 items (Box 54)
  - Models, assorted, 30 items (Box 69)
  - Models, miscellaneous, [item count?] (Box 71)
  - Mold, wooden, unidentified, 1 item (Box 52)
  - Molds, 1 item (Box 51)
  - Molds, miscellaneous, 9 items (Box 52)
  - Molds, 5 items (Box 56)
  - Molds, 4 items (Box 63)
  - Molds, 6 items (Box 85)
  - Unidentified small wooden pieces, 7 items (Box 56)
- Oversize packages
  Listed here, in box number order, are oversize boxes that contain material related to multiple clients, projects, or topics. Oversize boxes related to a single client, project, or topic are listed in the appropriate location in the inventory above.
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 1)
    Photographs of 1949 World’s Fair
    List of clients for sales presentation
    Statton Furniture - drawings
    Presentation of material sales, duplicate copy
    Furniture design patent, drawings, ink & photostat
    Howard & Schaffer decorative fabrics
  - Prints, miscellaneous (Oversize 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 4)
    Dupont - patent photo
    Heywood Wakefield - photos
    Knowles - Esquire shapes, Botanica pattern
    Iroquois China (1952) - presentation renderings for new items
    Kosta Glass - renderings
    Wurlitzer Accordion - sketches
    Wurlitzer Accordion - illustrations/designs
  - Silverware set (Oversize 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 6)
    Iroquois decorated final artwork - nasturtiums
    Photostats & script, book - "American Modern"
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 7)
    Cut out patterns & designs
    Photo - mural of J. Hull Flatware [MISSING 1/2008]
    Harker - clover pattern designs
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 8)
    Iroquois China - designs & drawings
    International Appliance - irons presentation
    Raymor Lamp - photos
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 9)
    Wurlitzer - accordion, piano, radio renderings
    Cornwall Dupont - patent photos & reprt
    R.W. - book, original artwork, picnic illustrations
    Wilkes-Barre Lace Co.
    Statton - sales promotion pictures & guide
  - Heywood, designs for furniture, rugs, drapery, fabrics (Oversize 10A, 10B)
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 11)
    Shwayder - chair renderings
    Mural - photos
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 12)
    Clocks
    Dupont - unused patterns
    Tilbury - flower & leaf sketches, large size
    Guide to "Easier Living" table setting chart
    Rustic dinnerware
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 15)
    Designs, patterns
    Dupont - presentation showroom
    Merganthaler Linotype
    Ravenware - presentation
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 16)
    Peerless Broilquick - accepted sketches
    Taiwan Handicraft - promotion center survey
    Paper novelty
    Englishtown - renderings
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 17)
    Plated patterns
    Sloane-Blabon Corp. - studies, tropical pattern
    Study of cat-tails for drapes
    Vietnam Dept. Store - exhibit publicity
    Flatware presentation
    Sterling China - presentation drawings (not used)
    Ravenware presentation - pewter designs
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 18)
    Peerless Broilquick - sketches
    Sears Roebuck - "Knock Down Furniture"
  - Drawings, clippings, and patterns (Oversize 19)
  - Oversize material (Oversize 20)
    American Modern - tablecloth designs
    Illustrations for "Easier Living"
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 22)
    Leacock (accepted designs)
    Illustrations/ blueprints of glassware
    Perspectives - front hall detail, cane hook drawings
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 23)
    Illustrations/ blueprints of dinnerware
    Northern Industrial Chemical - "Flair" dinnerware illustrations
    Vending machine designs
    World’s Fair, New York - food exhibition
  - Miscellaneous, weaving patterns; folding chair design; cardboard model of ski lodge layout (Oversize 24)
  - Painted designs (Oversize 26)
  - Kitchen originals, drawings and details (Oversize 27)
  - Folders for color plates A & B (Oversize 30)
  - Furniture illustrations and blueprints (Oversize 34)
  - Miscellaneous illustrations and paintings, 1939 (Oversize 35)
    Contents split into OS 35 and OS 45, Nov 2017.
  - Mural photos (Oversize 36)
  - Miscellaneous, floral drawings, placemats, newspaper/magazine clippings, retail sales presentation (Oversize 37)
  - Miscellaneous design studies, American Crystal, American Cyanamid, American Way (Oversize 38)
    A detailed list of the contents of this package is available in hard copy. Please contact the repository listed above for more information.
  - Silverware set (Oversize 42)
  - Miscellaneous illustrations and paintings (Oversize 45)